Guide to the Yale University Buildings and Grounds Negatives and Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University buildings and grounds negatives and photographs
1748-1919
RU 705
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The materials consist of photographs and negatives of maps, plans, and pictures of Yale buildings depicted between 1748-1919. The negatives are not dated.
General note
Yale Record Group 46-A (YRG 46-A), Records and materials broadly documenting Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and negatives of maps, plans, and pictures of Yale buildings depicted between 1748-1919. The negatives are not dated.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
College buildings; Universities and colleges -- Landscape architecture; Architectural records; Maps (documents); Photographs; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Photographs
  - Trumbull's Old Brick Row (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - SSS: Sachem Hall (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Silliman House, circa 1836 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tombstone -J. Hemingway (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Weir Hall, circa 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Old South Middle (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Old Library dedication tablets (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale Medical School (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Analytical Laboratory, circa 1847 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - First Chapel & Connecticut Hall (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sheffield Scientific (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Timothy Dwight (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wall Street, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - High Street, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - College Street, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Jonathan Edwards -dining hall (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Payne Whitney Gymnasium (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Phi Gamma Delta Hall (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Vanderbilt Hall (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - New Haven Green (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Maps of New Haven, circa1748 & 1847 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - New Haven, 1828 & 1830 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - New Haven & Yale Aerophotograph (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Yale & New Haven -Moses Bradford, circa 1802 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Yale College -Doolittle, circa 1807 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Yale College -Valois, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Yale University -Pope, circa 1919 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Joseph E. Sheffield Mansion, circa 1875 (Box 1, Folder 28)